smartpress.com 2019-03-16

# Privacy Policy | Smartpress Support

**Privacy Policy**  
**Commitment to Privacy**  
We at Smartpress.com understand the importance of protecting the privacy of our users. The information collected on the Smartpress.com website is used exclusively by Smartpress.com to market and improve the services we offer to our customers, to improve the Smartpress.com website content, and to contact you with updates to the website or for other marketing purposes directly related to your Smartpress.com customer relationship.

**Visitor Information**  
Certain areas of Smartpress.com, including those areas used to make purchases, require registration and/or a password for access. Information obtained from registered users of these areas may also be used for Smartpress.com marketing purposes, and cookies may be used in those and other areas, as described in this Policy. Information obtained in these areas may also be used in accordance with agreements governing access to and the use of the specific areas. In addition, visitors to Smartpress.com will need to register for a Smartpress.com Login user ID and password to use many of the interactive features on Smartpress.com as well as to make a purchase or file an order from Smartpress.com. Log file data and other information gathered from registered users of Smartpress.com are used to improve the Smartpress.com customer experience.

We collect the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, aggregate information on what pages consumers access or visit, information volunteered by the consumer (such as survey information and/or site registrations), name and address, telephone number, payment information (e.g., credit card number and billing address), including all pertinent information on our online order form.

The information Smartpress.com collects is used to improve the content of our Web page, used to customize the content and/or layout of our page for each individual visitor, and may be disclosed when legally required to do so, at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our Website and applicable laws or to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Website.

The Smartpress.com web server uses an extended log file format which captures: date and time of visit, referring address (location from which a visitor comes to Smartpress.com), type of Internet browser, and visitor’s IP address. (Each computer that connects to the Internet is assigned a unique number, an IP address, for identification purposes).

**Personal Information**  
Certain areas of Smartpress.com ask for personal information. Smartpress.com uses this personal information to aid in presenting its customers with a better interactive experience and to facilitate the customer’s ability to make purchases and orders from the Smartpress.com website. To register for a login user ID, your name, address, email address, and billing information are requested. This information is collected to help us further develop our services, to provide you access to valuable Smartpress.com Internet-based information and services, and to facilitate the billing process for those services if you elect to use them. Customers will have the ability to access and change the information which they have provided to Smartpress.com by use of the appropriate features on the Smartpress.com website.

**Use of Personal Information**  
The information collected through this site helps us identify the type of website content that our customers value, allowing us to market and improve the website and our services. The information is also used to send email notifications to customers about updates to the website, and to contact customers by other means for marketing and other purposes.

Under no circumstances will we give, sell, or otherwise distribute the information collected through this site to third parties outside of Smartpress.com and its subsidiaries (unless required by law). Smartpress.com uses an outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. We require our suppliers and vendors to conduct themselves in a manner consistent with this policy and our requirements.

**Information From Third Parties**  
If necessary, Smartpress.com obtains consumer information from third-party providers in order to improve the accuracy of our customer database and to increase our understanding of our customers or to identify potential customers. For example, we get updated addresses from the National Change of Address (NCOA) service to assist us in having the correct addresses for our customers.

**Cookies**  
With respect to cookies: We use cookies to record session information. Cookies are a series of data characters that, when programmed into a web site, is placed by the web server into the browser’s application folder on your computer. Once placed onto your machine, the cookie will allow the website to “recognize” you as a unique individual. Smartpress.com uses these cookies to associate individual customers with their information profiles. No personal information of any kind is stored in these cookies. They are only used by Smartpress.com to “remember” your user ID when you login to Smartpress.com on your computer. They are not passed on to any third parties.

**Links**

Our sites may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware of this fact when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that they visit which collects personally-identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

**Opt-Out Options**  
If you do not want to receive future e-mail from Smartpress.com, please let us know by e-mailing us at the following address: newsletter@smartpress.com or by following the “unsubscribe” links from a current email from us. Customers may prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected by e-mailing us at the above address. All opt-out requests will be honored, without question. All marketing communications from Smartpress.com will tell you how to stop receiving them.

If you supply us with your postal address online, you will only receive the information for which you provided us your address. If you supply us with your telephone numbers online, you will only receive contact from us with the information you have requested or regarding orders you have placed online.

Upon request, we provide site visitors with access to a description of information that we maintain about them. Visitors can request this information by email or contacting us at the address below. Upon request, we offer visitors the ability to have inaccuracies corrected in contact or financial information. Consumers can have this information corrected by sending us an email at the above address.

**Security**  
We always have security measures in place online and in our physical facilities to protect customer information and to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site. Because the security of your personal information is a high priority, we have taken numerous steps to ensure that it is processed confidentially, accurately, and securely. The Smartpress.com website uses encryption technology, such as Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, which is supported by the vast majority of modern Internet browsers. SSL technology represents the highest level of security available on the Internet, automatically encrypting information traveling over the Internet, verifying the identity of the transacting servers through certificates and digital signatures, and confirming that the integrity of the message content is maintained throughout its transmission. Smartpress.com cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us by email, and you do so at your own risk.

From time to time, Smartpress.com may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt-out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our website periodically.

If you feel that Smartpress.com is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us at the address below.  
950 Lake Drive , Chanhassen, MN 55317  
Smartpress.com reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time with or without notice. Please check back frequently in the event of changes.  
Your use of Smartpress.com constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy.
